<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xml:base="https://flohgro.com/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FlohGro&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://flohgro.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://flohgro.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>I code more than I write.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Fantastic Event Parser</title>
      <link>https://flohgro.com/fantastic-event-parser/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I extended the awesome &lt;em&gt;Fantastically Good Event Parser&lt;/em&gt; by @pdavisonreiber (original &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/fantastically-good-event-parser/1745?u=flohgro&quot;&gt;Drafts forum post&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://actions.getdrafts.com/a/1Lk&quot;&gt;action&lt;/a&gt;) to allow the users more control over the actually created event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It uses the same parsing technique so full credits to @pdavisonreiber for that logic! I added a prompt for each event the action will create where you can check the interpreted data and make adjustments if you want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I included an extended documentation on how to use the action in the directory. A few examples of events that will be recognized by the action:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Important discussion with coworkers tomorrow 9:00-11:30 /work alert 30min at Apple Park
Dinner sunday 19:00 for 3h /private at FavoritePizza
Workshop 2024-02-01 to 2024-02-03 /work at San Francisco
Call with Somebody today 17:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find the documentation and download it in the action directory&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://directory.getdrafts.com/a/2Og&quot;&gt;https://directory.getdrafts.com/a/2Og&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to discuss about the action head over to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/fantastic-event-parser/14766?u=flohgro&quot;&gt;Drafts forum&lt;/a&gt;. I also posted about it on &lt;a href=&quot;https://social.lol/@flohgro/111623974163344208&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; – let me know what you think ☺️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 21:52:11 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>FlohGro</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://flohgro.com/fantastic-event-parser/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drafts AI Tools</title>
      <link>https://flohgro.com/drafts-ai-tools/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt; added scripting support for OpenAI’s ChatGPT already in &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.getdrafts.com/changelog/#390&quot;&gt;version 39&lt;/a&gt; together with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/using-openai-chatgpt-with-drafts/14221&quot;&gt;forum post&lt;/a&gt; which contains some example actions what you can do with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was very excited about that because there are many use cases for AI within Drafts. Summarization, creation of ideas, spell-checking, translation or simply answering questions – you name it. I created a few actions using the scripting API for myself which were very useful for me. I wanted to enable more users without scripting knowledge to create their own actions to be used with this integration. It took me a while to figure out what could be a solution by being flexible enough at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I released the &lt;a href=&quot;https://directory.getdrafts.com/g/2PG&quot;&gt;AI Tools&lt;/a&gt; action group today. It contains a few ready-to-use actions and a template action to easily create actions for your own use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flohgro.com/assets/CleanShot-2024-01-16-at-00.34.-1ZHIXUrqrp0q.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My idea was to create a template action that users can duplicate and then configure for their own purposes. The action has three important configuration options that define what “question” is sent to ChatGPT with the option to include “input text” that e.g. should be translated and of course tell the underlying script, what to do with the response text from ChatGPT. The configuration is done with the so-called “Define Template Tag” steps in the action. They contain the available options so you can easily choose what you want. The action group description in the Drafts directory contains detailed information, on what the different options mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flohgro.com/assets/CleanShot-2024-01-16-at-00.34.-MLSaMzpyokyx.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to try the &lt;a href=&quot;https://directory.getdrafts.com/g/2PG&quot;&gt;AI Tools&lt;/a&gt; and create your own, just download the action group from the directory and make sure to read through the docs before using any of the actions or create your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really hope that the AI Tools action group is helpful for you and enables users to create helpful AI-powered actions for themselves without the need to script on their own. I would be interested to hear what you enjoy, what you dislike, and most importantly what use cases you created for yourself. I would be happy to hear from you on &lt;a href=&quot;https://social.lol/@flohgro/111761185368113113&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the hood the action runs another action from the action group which is not visible in the list that contains the full script – if you’re interested you can have a look at the action by navigating into the “manage action groups panel” and look for the “AIToolBuilderScript” action. The code of the script is available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/FlohGro-dev/drafts-actions/blob/main/aiToolBuilder.js&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 22:52:35 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>FlohGro</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://flohgro.com/drafts-ai-tools/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Task Toggler Action</title>
      <link>https://flohgro.com/task-toggler-action/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I’ve been creating a lot of checklists or just notes with tasks within &lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt;. I used an action that allows to toggle the states of these tasks in the selected range (either the line where the cursor is located or multiple selected lines). This worked but was not fitting my use cases. I also wanted the possibility to make a task out of a bullet point or a line with just text in it without creating another action that I need to trigger separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course I sat down and it took me embarrassingly long to script a (so far) perfectly working action for me. Using &lt;code&gt;md task toggler&lt;/code&gt; I only need to press one keyboard shortcut (or icon in the ActionBar) to toggle the state of the tasks in the selected range or add checkboxes to lines where they are missing.&lt;br&gt;
Of course the indentation of lines remains unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flohgro.com/assets/CleanShot-2024-03-08-at-22.16.-0ezUzsqq5avO.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;➡️ &lt;a href=&quot;https://directory.getdrafts.com/a/2QU&quot;&gt;GET THE ACTION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 20:47:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>FlohGro</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://flohgro.com/task-toggler-action/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raycast Extension for Drafts</title>
      <link>https://flohgro.com/raycast-extension-for-drafts/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I updated my Raycast extension for Drafts with the new command &lt;code&gt;Create Draft from Selection&lt;/code&gt; that will create a new draft from the currently selected text 🥳. It was a suggestion by a user of it, and I (finally) took some time to add it and really enjoy using it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever you want to create a new Draft with text from e.g. a webpage/another app/file contents/you name it, just select it and invoke the new command of the Raycast extension. This will immediately create a new Draft containing your selected text, and you can start taking further notes on it (or move it somewhere else).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can install the extension from the Raycast store if you’re not already using it: &lt;a href=&quot;https://raycast.com/FlohGro/drafts&quot;&gt;https://raycast.com/FlohGro/drafts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
If you do, it should get updated automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you have any further suggestions for the extension; I‘m happy to further improve it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, the process of developing an extension for Raycast is great and very well-documented. It was fine when I first created the extension but was refined and improved a lot. Now, I don’t need to fiddle around with GitHub a lot anymore since they introduced a „publish“ command to the tooling they provide. This simplifies creating the pull request to their repository a lot 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their API docs now (don’t know when it was added) include an AI that you can ask questions to – it helps a lot when you quickly want to search something but don’t know the exact terms/methods you have to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, the review of my changes was very fast; in not even 24h, the PR was approved by a member of the Raycast team and merged into the extensions repository 👍🏼.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 10:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>FlohGro</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://flohgro.com/raycast-extension-for-drafts/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joining the One a Month Club 😊</title>
      <link>https://flohgro.com/joining-the-one-a-month-club/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I stumbled across some posts on Mastodon and blogs I follow about „One a Month“. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bio.link/jarrod&quot;&gt;Jarrod&lt;/a&gt; has set up a cool site for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://oneamonth.club&quot;&gt;One a Month Club&lt;/a&gt; to round up all sites / people who are following this framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://manuelmorale.com&quot;&gt;Manuel Morale&lt;/a&gt; started that ‘movement’ on his blog saying:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently realized that tiers are the wrong approach. At least for me. I believe in kindness. I believe that if you decide to support something I do, you should get all the benefits, no matter how much you pay.“&lt;br&gt;
– Manuel Moreale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I totally agree with his belief in kindness, but as Robb also put it in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://rknight.me/blog/one-a-month-club/&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to paywall the things I make, those are better served being available to everyone“&lt;br&gt;
– Robb Knight&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has always been my approach and people who benefit from things I develop get „nothing“ but the satisfaction of making me smile. Of course there are regular costs (e.g. this website or the great social.lol instance on Mastodon by &lt;a href=&quot;https://omg.lol&quot;&gt;omg.lol&lt;/a&gt;) but the most expensive thing of course is my own time. I love creating tools and helping people improve and simplify their workflows so I never paywalled these things. On the other hand it’s really great to get some appreciation and a little compensation of the costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short: I added (or changed) membership tiers on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://ko-fi.com/flohgro&quot;&gt;ko-fi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://buymeacoffee.com/flohgro&quot;&gt;buymeacoffee&lt;/a&gt; to 1$ a month. I also changed the minimum amount to 1$ to join the people Jarrod listed on &lt;a href=&quot;https://oneamonth.club&quot;&gt;oneamonth.club&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing will change about the stuff I create and share, but if you want to support me on a regular basis, you can do so at the lowest possible cost. I really appreciate every single support I receive, replies / boosts on Mastodon, kind words via email and of course everyone who wants to support &lt;em&gt;One a Month&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 13:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>FlohGro</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://flohgro.com/joining-the-one-a-month-club/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QuickLink Opener</title>
      <link>https://flohgro.com/quicklink-opener/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Opening the same link(s) over and over again on different platforms can be annoying if you always have to type them or you need to rely on bookmarks or other apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bookmarks don’t work for me especially on iOS with the different Safari profiles that I use. These profiles are just not accessible enough on the iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course I created a Drafts action to solve this problem for me. &lt;strong&gt;QuickLink Opener&lt;/strong&gt; allows me to configure links that I often open in a simple configuration draft where I categorise them into different sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I want to open one of the configured links I just hit the action and select the category + url that I want to open. I immediately added the action to my Drafts widget in the Today View on iOS – to get really easy access to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;➡️ &lt;a href=&quot;https://directory.getdrafts.com/a/2Qo&quot;&gt;GET THE ACTION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 19:36:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>FlohGro</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://flohgro.com/quicklink-opener/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automating Readwise Highlights Import into Drafts</title>
      <link>https://flohgro.com/automating-readwise-highlights-import-into-drafts/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using Shortcuts and a Drafts Action you can automate the import of highlights from Readwise Reader into Drafts once a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I absolutely enjoy using &lt;a href=&quot;https://readwise.io/i/floh&quot;&gt;Readwise&lt;/a&gt; Reader as my RSS and read later service. However, I wanted to make the most of my highlights by importing them into &lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt; for review and processing. A while back, I created the &lt;a href=&quot;https://directory.getdrafts.com/a/2Mt&quot;&gt;import latest Readwise highlights&lt;/a&gt; action, which pulls all the new highlights into Drafts. The only downside was having to manually run this action, which was quite inconvenient and in the end of course didn’t work out..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily there is a solution to automatically run this action once every day using Shortcuts.&lt;br&gt;
My first attempt to set it up as a scheduled automation didn’t work since running the action requires Drafts to be opened. This isn’t always possible, especially when the device is locked.&lt;br&gt;
However, I found an effective workaround that involved setting up a personal automation to log the last time Drafts was opened in a file. This enables Shortcuts to determine whether Drafts had been opened that day and trigger the import action accordingly.&lt;br&gt;
Testing it for the first time – I quickly noticed that the original action for importing highlights always loaded a Draft into the editor, potentially disrupting your workflow. To address this issue, I created a modified version of the action specifically for automated execution. This tweaked version imports the new highlights without interfering with your tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in automating the process of importing Readwise highlights or any other action you (want to) run on a regular basis, here is what you need to do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get the &lt;a href=&quot;https://directory.getdrafts.com/a/2Sa&quot;&gt;import latest Readwise highlights (automated)&lt;/a&gt; action (of course this is not necessary if you want to run another action)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download and set up the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/4e9f6c7995e94487997b7c2f1a45a696&quot;&gt;Import Reading Highlights Drafts Automation&lt;/a&gt; Shortcut (you need to select the action you want to run during installation).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a personal automation in Shortcuts that triggers the Shortcut as soon as you open Drafts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 11:00:31 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>FlohGro</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://flohgro.com/automating-readwise-highlights-import-into-drafts/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AirPods 4 ANC - My Impressions</title>
      <link>https://flohgro.com/airpods-4-anc-my-impressions/</link>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like the slightly smaller case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They feel very comfortable – can’t tell a real difference to the previous generations (but I never had issues with comfort)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really enjoy the conversation awareness feature – it even pauses podcasts when you have a “longer” conversation – but not all people respond quick enough for this to trigger 😂&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ANC is better than I thought but worse than I hoped 😝 but truly speaking it’s perfectly fine for what I need (I have AirPods Max for working at home with great ANC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adaptive audio is weird – for now I prefer real ANC or full transparency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 19:59:57 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>FlohGro</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://flohgro.com/airpods-4-anc-my-impressions/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catppuccin Drafts Themes</title>
      <link>https://flohgro.com/catppuccin-drafts-themes/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I took some time to create some &lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt; themes inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://catppuccin.com&quot;&gt;Catppuccin&lt;/a&gt;. I already enjoy using the Mocha theme in VS Code so it was only a matter of time to finally create one for my favorite app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did my best to stick to the style-guide and I think they turned out great! Check them out and let me know if you like them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flohgro.com/assets/Saturday-30-Nov-2024-111949-SoVdUJbteaFw.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshots of the different Catppuccin themes for Drafts&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download them in the Drafts directory&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://directory.getdrafts.com/t/2Vn&quot;&gt;Catppuccin Frappé&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://directory.getdrafts.com/t/2Vo&quot;&gt;Catppuccin Latte&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://directory.getdrafts.com/t/2Vp&quot;&gt;Catppuccin Macchiato&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://directory.getdrafts.com/t/2Vm&quot;&gt;Catppuccin Mocha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 09:29:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>FlohGro</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://flohgro.com/catppuccin-drafts-themes/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drafts 46 - Automate!</title>
      <link>https://flohgro.com/drafts-46-automate/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt; Version 46 was released today. In this post, I will highlight new features and my personal highlights of the release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flohgro.com/assets/Thursday-12-Dec-2024-201012-Y0bAJGRP2SFo.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I &lt;a href=&quot;https://social.lol/@flohgro/113534112362382431&quot;&gt;dipped my toes&lt;/a&gt; into &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.getdrafts.com/docs/extending/development/syntax-format&quot;&gt;Syntax development&lt;/a&gt; for Drafts. I have no need to make big changes but I wanted to define some custom link definitions to e.g. run an action with &lt;code&gt;[[r:process INBOX]]&lt;/code&gt;or open a tag filter with &lt;code&gt;[[t:project::active]]&lt;/code&gt; – it is also published to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://directory.getdrafts.com/s/2Vj&quot;&gt;directory&lt;/a&gt; (and I maintain it in the respective &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/FlohGro-dev/drafts-syntaxes&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;). When I added those link definitions I quickly noticed that the URL scheme that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.getdrafts.com/docs/automation/urlschemes#search&quot;&gt;/search&lt;/a&gt; URL scheme did default to the inbox folder in Drafts. What I wanted was to directly jump to the &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; folder to see every draft tagged with the given tag. After requesting the additional parameter it was added with this release and it works great. Now you can pass a folder parameter to force switching the folder tab in the draft list. E.g. &lt;code&gt;drafts://search?tag=project&amp;amp;folder=all&lt;/code&gt; will filter the drafts list for all drafts tagged with &lt;em&gt;project&lt;/em&gt;. I use this e.g. in my Weekly Review checklist together with the mentioned syntax it is easily possible to quickly filter for all drafts that are tagged with &lt;code&gt;project::active&lt;/code&gt;. Another way I use this is to link to special searches from routine tasks in Todoist that open a specific predefined search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I don’t have a big personal use for it right now a new feature in Drafts 46 is Text-to-Speech. The described use case in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-46-released-text-to-speech-background-actions/15670/8?u=flohgro&quot;&gt;forum&lt;/a&gt; e.g. as snippet library for often used phrases for verbally challenged users is an exceptionally great example. I appreciate that features like this are added to Drafts and extend its capabilities in ways I never thought about. If you want to find out more about this have a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.getdrafts.com/docs/editor/text-to-speech&quot;&gt;guide&lt;/a&gt; which also includes some example actions that are ready to use to e.g. read the currently selected text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite new feature however is the new “Run Action in Background” shortcuts action.&lt;br&gt;
In fact, these are two new actions to either run a Drafts action on a given draft or on a provided text (which can be empty).&lt;br&gt;
This allows triggering Drafts’ actions from shortcuts without making Drafts the active app.&lt;br&gt;
A few months ago I found a (tacky) solution to &lt;a href=&quot;https://flohgro.com/automation/automating-readwise-highlights-import-into-drafts/&quot;&gt;automate importing my Readwise highlights into Drafts&lt;/a&gt;. With this release, you can now create a scheduled automation that runs Drafts actions at a specific time of the day. Another example could be a tickler file action as discussed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/is-it-possible-to-make-a-tickler-file-action/15578/5?u=flohgro&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; forum thread. The background execution has some restrictions. Actions that require user interactions (e.g. responding to a prompt) will not work – as stated in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-46-released-text-to-speech-background-actions/15670#p-44685-background-actions-with-caveats-4?u=flohgro&quot;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; Drafts will try to not display actions when you select the action in the Shortcuts editor but since evaluating this e.g. for scripted actions is not an easy task this is not bulletproof.&lt;br&gt;
If you have a use case I recommend just trying to run the Action from a Shortcut without setting up the automation first. Then double-check if you see the expected result in Drafts and set up the automation afterward. The potential for this feature is big! If you’re using Daily Notes you can let Drafts create that note daily (or weekly/monthly) in the background and once you open the app they will already be there. I will try to automate posting quotes to Mastodon with this feature.&lt;br&gt;
Of course, this is not only relevant for automation, this can also be used to run Drafts actions in other shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another solid release of Drafts – if you want to dive into the discussions of the new release head over to the announcement &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-46-released-text-to-speech-background-actions/15670?u=flohgro&quot;&gt;in the forum&lt;/a&gt;. I’m interested in your use cases for the new &lt;em&gt;Run Action in Background&lt;/em&gt; shortcuts action step – whether as automation or integrated into any other shortcut. Share them in the forum or send them over to me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://social.lol/@flohgro&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/flohgro.bsky.social&quot;&gt;Bluesky&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:49:24 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>FlohGro</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://flohgro.com/drafts-46-automate/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>